(Sincro: wyxchari)
Right. Now!
好, 走！
No. Look, out there.
不, 看, 那边
I don't see anything.
我什么也没看见
In that patch of moonlight. I told you I'd seen them!
在那边月光下．我说过我见过它们的！
Ah! That proves it! I wasn't seeing things!
啊！这有证明了！我没有幻视!
Medok - the guards. They'll hear you.
Medok - 警卫啊, 他们听见你了
It doesn't matter. They can't lock me up again.
没关系．他们不能再锁着我了
Now I can prove it. We know they're real.
现在我可以证明了, 我们知道它们是真实的了
Medok.
Medok.﻿
Medok. I know you're in there. Come out quietly.
Medok, 我知道你在里面, 快点出来
You can put that gun away. I'm coming.
你把枪口拿开, 我出来
Who's with you?
跟谁在一起？
The Doctor.
博士
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Don't waste time. Come on over here.
别浪费时间, 到这里来
Stay where you are.
待在原地别动
Listen, I came out to show you.
听着, 我出来展示给你看
Stand still!
站住别动！
It's the Macra, Ola! They are real!
是 Macra 啊, Ola! 它们是真的！
Ask the Doctor. He'll tell you.
问问博士, 他会告诉你的
Yes, I think I can confirm...
是的, 我想我可以证实...
We don't want to know what the strangers think.
我们不想知道这些异乡人的想法
Well, it might be as well to...
fixme
Ha, ha, ha. Where do you think you're going?
哈哈哈, 你觉得你在往哪里走?fixme
I just thought I'd go and have a look.
我只是想去看一眼
Stay where you are. Guards - search him.
待在原地别动．警卫 - 搜他的身
What will they do to us?
他们要对我们做什么？
I'll tell you. You're going before the Pilot.
我来告诉你．你们要去见领航员
You are in the company of an escaped criminal.
And you were out in the Colony at night.
你们跟逃走的罪犯在一起．而且你们夜间出来到园区了
I'm sorry, Doctor. I thought he'd listen to reason.
我很抱歉, 博士．我以为他会听我们讲道理的
Reason's the last thing a man like Ola will listen to.
像 Ola 这样的人, 道理是最后才会听取的东西
You're going to be in trouble, and it's my fault.
你会陷入麻烦了, 都是我的错
Silence! Pilot's headquarters. Move!
安静！领航员总部, 走！
...shifts to stand by for greater efforts
during working hours.
...班次可以为工作时间内的最大产出做好准备
The gas from the pits must be kept
in constant supply at even greater pressures.
即使在更大的压力下, 从矿坑采集的瓦斯必须保持持续供应
Remember the life of the colony is dependent upon
this gas. All industry and activity...
记住殖民地的生活都依赖于这种瓦斯, 所有的工业和活动...
Emergency call. Emergency call.
紧急呼叫．紧急呼叫
Yes. Go ahead, emergency.
收到．请讲, 什么紧急情况？
Ola requests audience immediately.
Ola 请求立即接见, Ola 请求立即接见
Look, I'm extremely busy.
Unless this is a major crisis, I really don't...
听着, 我非常忙．除非这是重大危机, 否则我真的不...
Medok has been taken prisoner
and one of the strangers has been captured with him.
Medok 已经被抓住了, 还有一个异乡人一同被抓
Bring the stranger in.
把异乡人带进来
Good evening, Pilot.
Oh, what a very nice office you have here.
晚上好, 领航员．哦, 你这件办公室真的很漂亮啊
Now what's this all about, Doctor?
这都是怎么回事, 博士？
Well, I...
这个, 我...
We found both of them in the new buildings, Pilot.
我们在新大楼里面发现了他们俩, 领航员
At night? How did he get there?
Wasn't there a guard on his sleeping quarters?
在晚上？他怎么跑到那里去的？他的休息间没有一个警卫吗？
All my guards were out looking for Medok, Pilot.
我所有的警卫都派出来搜寻 Medok 了, 领航员
I see. Very well. You may leave us, Ola.
我明白了．很好, 你可以走了, Ola
I will conduct the investigation myself.
我自己来调查
Oh, forgive me. This is interesting -
a telescopic viewing machine, hmm?
哦, 原谅我．这很有意思 - 这台机器是个望远镜, 嗯？
I imagine you can keep track
on the entire Colony from here
我猜想你可以从这里跟踪整个殖民地的事情
and direct intercommunication between all parts.
可以直接与所有部分通讯
Hmm. Very up-to-date, I imagine.
嗯, 很现代, 我觉得
Excellent, excellent. And what...
非常好, 非常好．这是...
You don't seem to realize how serious this business is,
Doctor. You have committed a crime.
你似乎还没意识到事情有多严重, 博士．你犯了罪了
A crime?
犯罪？
What were you doing with Medok?
You know he's a dangerous man.
你跟 Medok 一起在做什么？你知道他是一个危险的人
I'm not so sure, Pilot.
我可没这么确定, 领航员
You have already been told.
你们都已经被告知了
He has refused to cooperate and to obey orders.
He suffers from hallucinations.
他拒绝合作拒绝服从命令, 他受幻觉所折磨
Ah, that's the point. Does he?
啊, 说到点上了．他有吗？
And what exactly do you mean by that?
你这么说到底是什么意思？
Let me perhaps explain.
也许让我来解释一下
Well, what is it now? I've already said
that I don't want to be interrupted.
嗯, 又什么事？我已经说过了, 我不想被打扰
Ola reporting, Pilot.
Ola 有事汇报, 领航员
Well, what is it?
好吧, 什么事情？
Medok has made a statement.
It completely changes the situation.
Medek 陈述了情况, 彻底改变了事态
Oh, very well. Bring him in.
噢, 很好．带他进来
I hope you are not going to listen to everything
that Medok tells you?
我期望, 不是他所有的话, 你都会相信吧？
Why, Doctor? Are you afraid of something he might say?
为什么, 博士？你是害怕他可能会说些什么吗？
Well, in his state of mind he might say anything.
哦, 在他目前的精神状态, 他可能什么都说
Doctor. How have they been treating you?
博士, 他们没把你怎么样吧？
Silence!
安静！
Perfectly all right, thank you.
完全没事, 谢谢你
Medok's made a further statement,
Pilot. It's about the Doctor.
Medok 做出了详细的供词, 领航员．是关于博士的
Ah.
啊
Aha.
啊哈
Yes, Medok?
是吗, Medok?
The Doctor wasn't helping me.
He was trying to make me give myself up.
博士不是在帮我．他一直在劝我自首
Well, that was extremely brave.
Why didn't you tell us this?
哦, 那可真是非常勇敢．为什么你之前不告诉我们这个？
Well, as a matter of fact...
这个, 事实上...
Captain Ola didn't give him a chance.
Ola 队长并没有给他机会
I see. Well, it seems we owe you an apology, Doctor.
我明白了．这样, 看来我们欠一个道歉, 博士
It's better we tell the truth, Doctor.
我们都说实话最好了, 博士
Yes. Thank you Medok. I... I quite understand.
是的, 谢谢你 Medok．我...我很明白
Take him away.
把他带走
Come on Medok.
来吧 Medok
Well, I'm extremely sorry about it, Doctor,
and of course you're free to go.
我对此真的很抱歉, 博士．而且你当然可以走了
What will happen to Medok?
Medok 会怎么样？
Oh. Well, he'll be taken back to the hospital
for correction.
哦, 他会被带回医院, 进行矫正
He'll be given another course of treatment.
他会再接一个疗程的治疗
And when he returns to the Colony,
Medok will be a changed man.
而当 Medok 返回殖民地的时候, 他就会是一个新人了
He will cooperate and he will obey orders.
He'll be just like the rest of us.
他会变得合作, 会服从命令．他会跟我们其他人一样
Why do you want everyone to be the same?
为什么你们想要每个人都一样？
Doctor, this colony was founded many centuries ago
博士, 这个殖民地是很多个世纪以前建立的
by our ancestors who came from the Earth planet,
like your young friends.
我们的祖先来自地球, 跟你的年轻朋友们一样
Our ancestors believed in the virtues of healthy happiness
我们的祖先信仰健康幸福的美德
and we have tried to keep their ideals alive.
而我们一直试图保持他们的理想不灭
Sometimes, alas, it is necessary to use force.
有些时候, 唉, 不得不使用武力
The Doctor will be returning to his quarters now.
The Doctor's escort is ready.
博士现在可以返回他的房间了, 他的护卫已经就绪了
Well, I'm sorry to have disturbed you, Doctor,
and many thanks again for your help.
好了, 我很抱歉这事烦扰了你, 博士．再次非常感谢你的帮助
Not at all. Thank you. Goodnight.
没什么．谢谢你, 晚安
Oh, I'm so sorry.
哦, 我很抱歉
Goodnight.
晚安
The Doctor and his friends are to be given
the advantage of high powered adaption at once.
fixme
They must begin to think like members of the Colony.
他们必须开始像殖民地的其他人员一样思考
They are to have deep sleep and thinking patterns.
他们要有深度睡眠和思维模式
We cannot have criticism from these strangers!
The work to do it - it must begin immediately.
我们不能容忍这些异乡人的非难！这项工作 - 必须马上开始
Emergency order from Control, top priority.
Are all the cubicles connected?
来自管理员的紧急指令, 最高优先级．所有的格子间都连好了吗？
The rest cubicles for the four strangers
are all connected for deep sleep and thought patterns.
四个异乡人的休息间都已经为深度睡眠和思维模式连接好了
Very good. The process is to begin immediately.
Your instructions are being carried out.
很好．这个过程立即开始．你的指令已经下发下去了
That is good. This is an emergency.
Control must be believed and obeyed!
这很好．这是紧急情况, 必须信任并服从管理员！
No one on the Colony believes in Macra!
There is no such thing as Macra!
这个殖民地没谁会相信 Macra 的事, 没有 Macra 这种东西！
Macra do not exist! There are no Macra!
Macra 不存在！没有 Macra!
The sleeper must relax and believe everything
in the Colony is good and beautiful.
睡者必须放松, 相信这个殖民地所有事情都是美好漂亮的
You must accept it without question.
You must obey orders.
你必须毫不置疑地接受这个, 你必须服从命令
The leaders of the Colony know what is best.
这个殖民地的领导者知道什么是最好的
In the morning when you wake up
you will be given some work.
到了早上你们醒来, 你们会被分配工作
You will be glad to obey.
You will question nothing in the Colony.
你们会很高兴地服从．你们不会置疑这个殖民地的任何事情
Ben? Ben?
Ben? Ben?﻿
Huh? What is it?
哈？什么事？
I heard something.
我听到了什么声音
Oh, you're always hearing something.
哦, 你总是能听到什么
I never heard a voice like this before. Ben?
我以前从没有听到这样的声音．Ben？
I'm asleep.
我睡着了
It was evil, Ben - an evil voice
很邪恶的, Ben - 一个邪恶的声音
An evil that spoke so gently and yet...
yet I almost believed what it said.
一个邪恶的声音在轻声说话, 而且...我几乎就相信了它所说的
Oh, look, mate. Get some sleep.
We got a hard day's work ahead of us tomorrow.
噢, 看啊, 老兄．睡一会儿吧．我们明天还有一整天的苦活儿呢
Why do you say that?
你为什么这么说？
Well, we've got to do something to help in the Colony.
We can't just eat their nosh without helping out.
我们得帮殖民地做点什么．我们不能吃着他们的, 什么也不帮
You sound just like that voice, Ben.
你听起来正像那个声音, Ben
Oh, what are you on about? This colony's all right.
It won't be too bad to work here.
噢, 你在说什么啊？这个殖民地很好．在这里工作不会太差
I never heard you talk that way before, Ben.
我以前从没有听你这样说过, Ben
You will not resist the sleeping gas.
Breathe deeply.
你不会抵制睡眠瓦斯．深深呼吸
In the morning, when you wake, you will obey.
到了早上, 等你醒来, 你会服从
Wake up, Polly.
醒醒, Polly
Doctor? What on earth are you doing?
博士？你到底在做什么啊？
I've been scotching a rumour.
Or should I say, scorching.
我一直在扑灭谣言, 或许我该说fixme
What happened?
怎么了？
Polly, I think you've been listening to
some very bad advice.
Polly, 我想你一直在听一些非常不好的建议
But I've been asleep.
但我一直在睡觉
Yes, I know you have. Fast asleep. Very fast asleep.
是的, 我知道你在睡．睡的很熟, 非常熟
Polly, do you smell anything? A sort of sweet perfume?
Polly, 你闻到什么了没？一种甜甜的香水味？
No.
没有
Never mind. Polly, I want you to forget everything
that you've been dreaming.
别管了．Polly, 我要你忘记你做梦时的所有事情
Why do you say that?
你为什么这么说？
Well, it's just possible that you've been given
a series of orders while you've been asleep.
哦, 只是有可能在你睡着的时候, 你被灌输了一系列的命令
You know, do this, do that, do the other thing.
你知道的, 做这个, 做那个, 做其它事情
My advice to you is don't do anything of the sort.
我给你的建议是这类事情都不做
Don't just be obedient.
Always make up your own mind.
不要单纯地服从．永远要自己做决定．
What am I thinking of? Ben and Jamie!
我在想什么呢？Ben 和 Jamie!
Hello, Doctor. Is it morning?
你好, 博士．到早上了？
No, not yet. Nearly so.
不, 还没有．快了
What are you up to?
你要干什么？
Well, by my calculations, there should be
a thin strand of wire in the wall here,
哦, 根据我的计算, 在墙内这里会有一根细电线
like a nerve tapping the subconscious of the human brain.
像一个神经一样搭在人类大脑的潜意识上
Lay off, mate. You'll find yourself on a charge.
放下, 老兄．你会面临指控的
Should be here somewhere. Ah!
应该在这里某处, 哈！
Pack it in, Doctor. The way you mess about
you could do some damage.
fixme放回去, 博士．你这样乱来, 会损坏东西的
Better some damage than loss of will power.
损坏一点东西好过意志力丧失
What are you on about? Look, get out of it.
It's against the law.
你在搞些什么？快, 出来, 这是违反法律的
What law?!
什么法律?!
The law of the Colony. Don't do that!
殖民地的法律．别这么干！
Now you'll get chucked in jail.
现在你会被赶进监狱了
What's the matter with you, Ben?
Since when did you start to worry?
你怎么回事, Ben? 你从什么时候开始学会担心了？
He thinks he knows best all the time,
but this time he's wrong.
他总觉得他一直最明白, 但这次他错了
Hey, what's all the noise?
嘿, 刚才是什么声音这么吵？
Jamie, how did you sleep?
Jamie, 你睡得怎么样？
Oh, very badly, Doctor.
I told Ben I kept hearing wee voices.
哦, 非常差, 博士．我跟 Ben 说过我一直听到有人轻声说活
That's a good sign. That means they haven't
been able to get very deeply into your brain.
这是个好信号．意味着他们进入你的大脑还没有很深
Eh? I don't understand?
诶？我不明白
I'll show you. Watch this.
我展示给你看, 看着这个
You're fools, all of you! Just look what you've done!
你们这些蠢人, 全都是！看看你都干了些什么！
You've smashed up all this equipment!
你们把所有的设备都砸烂了！
Yes, but look here. If they were trying to
make us believe a whole load of rubbish...
是的, 但看看这里．如果他们试图要让我们相信所有这一堆垃圾...
Rubbish? It's not rubbish.
Control knows what's best for us.
垃圾？这不是垃圾．管理员知道怎样对我们最好
They want us to cooperate. We should be helping.
他们想让我们合作．我们应该帮忙
What's the matter with you Ben?
This doesn't sound like you at all.
你怎么回事, Ben? 听起来完全不像你
We should learn to obey. The Doctor's causing trouble.
I'm going to turn him in.
我们应该学着服从．博士在制造麻烦, 我应该检举他
You don't know what you're doing, Ben.
你不知道你在做什么, Ben
Get off me!
别拉我！
What's the matter with him?
他怎么会是
I'm very much afraid I'm too late.
恐怕我一直太迟了！
Ben!
Ben!﻿
Let go of me.
放开我!
Ben!
Ben!﻿
Guards!
警卫!
Don't let him go.
别放他走
No, it's no use, Jamie.
不, 这没用的, Jamie
But we cannot let him go, Doctor.
但我们不能让他走, 博士
You'll have to. Violence will get you nowhere.
你不得不．暴力不会给你带来任何东西
Doctor, he's going to go and tell the guards.
We've got to get you out of here.
博士, 他会跑去告诉警卫．我们得带你离开这里
We can't leave Ben.
我们不能扔下 Ben
But he betrayed you.
但他背叛了你
No, no. Not Ben. He's not in control of his actions.
不, 不, 不是Ben．不是他自己在控制他的行动
He's been given a series of instructions
and he can't help himself.
他被灌输了一系列的指令, 他管不住自己
Yes but he...
是的, 但是他...
That's Him! He prodded about in the wall
and smashed up our equipment.
就是他！他在墙上乱砸, 破坏了我们的设备
This time we've got the evidence,
and from one of your own friends. Come on, Doctor.
这次我们有证据了, 还是你自己的朋友提供的．来吧, 博士
Leave him alone.
放开他
Get out of my way. That's an order.
别挡着我, 这是命令
I take orders from no one but the Doctor.
我不接受任何的的命令, 除了博士
All right, you're coming too. Get out, both of you!
好吧, 你也来．出来, 你们俩！
Thank you, Jamie, but I'd better go with Captain Ola.
谢谢你, Jamie, 但我最好跟 Ola 队长走
But Doctor, what will they do to you?
但是博士, 他们会把你怎么样？
He should be in that hospital of yours.
他应该进你们那个医院
You traitor. You...
你个叛徒, 你...
That's enough!
够了！
The hospital. He needs correction more than Medok does.
医院．他比 Medok 更需要矫正
You wish to cooperate. You have seen no strange creatures.
你愿意合作．你没见过奇怪的生物
You will work hard and happily. Hard and happily.
你会辛苦而快乐的工作, 辛苦而快乐
You wish to cooperate. You have seen no strange creatures.
你愿意合作．你没见过奇怪的生物
It's a very difficult case, I'm afraid.
这是个很棘手的病例, 我觉得
Nothing much we can do. He's too far gone to help.
我们做不了什么．他走得太远, 没法帮
No, he'll never be happy like the rest of us.
不, 他永远不会像我们一样幸福
All we can do is send him to the pits for life.
我们所能做的, 就是送他去矿坑终身劳动
Can't hide the truth.
隐藏不了事实
Yes, what is it? What's that? The Doctor?
嗯, 什么事？那是什么？博士？
I'll come at once. Keep at it.
我立刻过来．fixme
What did you do it for? The Doctor's our friend.
你这么做为了什么？博士是我们的朋友
I had to do my duty.
我必须履行我的职责
Well, you go on doing it, then.
好, 那你继续你的职责
I'm going to go and find out where the others have gone.
我要走了, 去看看其他人都去哪里了
Look, Polly, you'd better stay here.
听着, Polly, 你最好待在这里
Go on, report me.
去啊, 揭发我
Now look. Come back, Polly.
现在看着, 回来, Polly
Polly! Polly!
Polly! Polly!﻿
Polly, where are you? Polly? You'll be in trouble.
Polly, 你在哪里? Polly? 你会惹麻烦的
Don't fool about, Polly. You must obey Control.
别犯傻了, Polly．你必须服从于管理员
Polly?
Polly?﻿
Stop!
停下！
Leave me alone.
放开我
You're coming back to the guard.
你要回来fixme
What's the matter with you, Ben? Wake up!
你怎么回事啊, Ben! 醒醒!
You're coming with me, girl. You broke the Colony law.
你得跟我来, 姑娘．你违反了殖民地法律
What's the matter with you?
你怎么回事？
There's nothing there.
那里什么也没有
But, there was! I saw it!
A huge face, like an insect, or a giant crab.
但, 刚才有, 我看见了！巨大的面孔, 像一个大昆虫, 或者巨型的螃蟹
It was horrible and it was looking at us and...
and... and it had claws.
它太恐怖了, 它看着我们, 而且...它还有大钳子
Claws like we saw on the time scanner.
就像我们在时间扫描仪上看见的大钳子
There's nothing there. Come on.
那里什么也没有．快来
No, not that way.
不, 别去那边
Look you're just trying to dodge off.
看来你是想找借口跑掉
No, no. Please no. I'm not, but... but please look.
不不, 请不要．我不是,但是...求你看看
There is nothing there!
那里什么也没有!
Ben.
Ben﻿
What is it?
那是什么东西?
I... I don't know.
我...我不知道
Well, what are we going to do?
那, 我们该怎么办？
There is nothing evil or harmful in this colony.
殖民地内没有什么邪恶或者有害的东西
How can you believe that, studge?
你怎么还相信那个呢？
It stands to reason. It's safe.
There is nothing here!
它有道理啊．这里是安全的．这里什么也没有!
Ben, what is this? Get it off me, Ben!
It's got my foot! Ben, help!
Ben, 这是什么？弄走它, Ben! 它抓住我的脚了！Ben, 帮我！
Oh, it was horrible!
噢, 太可怕了
It's all right. I think it's going away.
没事了, 我觉得它走掉了
Ben, behind you! There's another one!
Ahh! Ben, they're all around us!
Ben, 在你后面！还有一个！啊！Ben, 我们四周都是！
Polly, you make a run for it, and I'll keep them here.
Polly, 你找机会跑出去, 我来跟它们周旋
No, you won't stand a chance.
不, 你一点机会也没有的
We can't stop here. Come on, quick! Ahh!
我们不能在这里停下．来吧, 快！啊！
Ahh!
啊！
You have destroyed three nerve circuits, Doctor.
你毁坏了三个神经电路, 博士
You have burned them out. What have you to say?
你把它们都烧坏了．你有什么可说的？
Rather neat, don't you think?
fixme很利落, 你觉得呢？
And so simple. I did it with this.
而且很简单．我用这个干的
You admit it?
你承认了？
I'm proud of it.
我对此很自豪
What is it? What's the matter?
怎么了？出了什么问题？
My dear Pilot, your wall? Even you were subjected to
this form of subconscious control?
我亲爱的领航员, 你的墙吗？即便是你也要接受这样的潜意识控制吗？
Leave that alone.
别动那个
That's better.
好多了
You will be punished for this.
你会为此得到惩罚
The least you can do is to say thank you.
你至少可以说声＂谢谢＂
Pilot!
领航员！
What is it?
什么事？
It's the young man who reported the Doctor, Pilot.
是那个年轻人举报了博士, 领航员
What about him?
他怎么样了？
He has another report, Pilot. An urgent one.
他有另外一件事要报告, 领航员．很紧急的
Very well, Ola, you may leave. I will deal with it.
很好, Ola, 你可以走了．我来处理吧
Who are you stabbing in the back this time?
你是什么人啊, 一直在背后捅刀子？
Polly? Polly? What's the matter?
Polly? Polly? 什么情况？
Doctor, it was horrible. A great insect, like...
like a crab.
博士, 太可怕了．一个巨大的昆虫, 就像...像一个螃蟹
It got hold of me. Ben got me free.
它抓住了我．Ben 帮我挣脱了
Ben did?
Ben 干的？
And he was nearly killed himself.
而且他几乎害死了自己
Silence. Did you protect the girl from such creatures?
安静．是你保护了这个姑娘没受这种生物伤害？
She ran away. I went after her.
她当时逃跑了, 我去追她
Did you protect her, and were there such creatures?
是你保护了她吗, 而且有那样的生物吗？
No. There were no such creatures.
不是．没有那样的生物
Ben!
Ben!﻿
There are no such things as Macra.
没有 Macra 这样的东西
But you saw them!
但你看见它们了!
There were no such creatures!
There are no such things as Macra!
没有这样的生物！没有 Macra 这种东西！
Don't blame him, Polly.
没怪他, Polly
But you heard him.
但你听到他说的了
I told you. Ben has come under control
of the evil forces
我跟你说, Ben 已经邪恶力量控制住了之下
at the heart of this colony.
那东西在这个殖民地的中心
That is quite untrue. Control always acts for the best.
这是相当不实的．管理员总是按最佳结果行动
Who is Control?
管理员是谁？
You've seen our Controller.
你已经见过我们的管理员了
Have I? I don't remember.
见过吗？我不记得
Well switch on then. We've nothing to hide.
那打开吧, 我们没有什么可隐藏的
Controller speaking. We know everything that's happened.
这里是管理员．我们知道所发生的一切
The poor girl has had hallucinations.
那个可怜的姑娘产生了幻觉
That's not the Controller.
That's just a picture of a man.
那不是管理员, 那只不过是一个人的照片
It is a picture of our Controller.
这是我们管理员的照片
Well, where is he? I'll wager he doesn't exist.
那, 他在哪儿？我打赌他并不存在
Of course he does.
他当然存在
Well, let's see him then.
好, 那我们去见他
That's not necessary.
这并没有必要
Well, I don't believe he's there.
那, 我不信他在那里
Of course he is, you've heard his voice.
他当然是, 你听到他的声音了
Why don't you show him to us then?
那你为什么不让他见我们？
Well all right. If you wish, I'll ask.
好, 行吧．如果你相见, 我问问
Ah, as you can hear, Control,
they...they ask to see you in person.
啊, 你应该听见了, 管理员．他们...他们要求见你, 面对面
That set the cat among the pigeons.
这是兴风作浪fixme
They've not got him there.
他们那里并没有那样一个人
This is your Controller. This is your Controller.
这里是你们的管理员, 这里是你们的管理员
But he's an old man.
但他是一个老人
Well, now you've seen the Controller.
好了吧, 现在你们见过管理员了
Well let him speak.
那让他说话
Be silent! That is an order!
安静！这是命令！
Let him speak.
让他说话
Be silent!
安静！
Ah, he's not giving the orders. He can't talk.
啊, 他不能下发命令, 他不会说话
This is the man. You will hear him speak.
就是这个人, 你们会听到他说话
Speak, Controller, speak!
说啊, 管理员, 说啊！
Speak? Am I to speak?
说话？fixme
Tell the strangers to believe and obey!
让异乡人相信, 让他们服从！
I... I will tell them. I will tell them.
I... I'll do what you say.
我...我会告诉他们, 我会告诉他们的．你说什么我都照做
Keep away. Don't touch me. I'll obey.
离远点, 别碰我．我会服从的
What's that? What's happening!
那是什么？发生什么事了？
Doctor, that was it - that thing in the picture!
博士, 那就是了 - 图片里面的那个东西！
That was the claw! They're in control.
就是那个夹子！他们在管理员体内fixme
Take them out of here. They are condemned to the pits!
把他们带离这里！他们被判去矿坑！
Macra!
Take them away!
把他们带走！
They're in control!